<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://apps.nextcloud.com/schema/apps/info.xsd">
	<id>talkbot</id>
	<name>Talk-Bot</name>
	<name lang="ja">Talk-Bot</name>

	<summary>Chat with Claude, Gemini or any OpenAI-compatible model right inside Nextcloud Talk</summary>
	<summary lang="ja">Nextcloud Talk の中で Claude / Gemini / OpenAI互換モデルと会話できるボット</summary>

	<description><![CDATA[
**Talk-Bot** turns any Nextcloud Talk conversation into an AI chat.

Enable the app, put your API key in the admin settings, and switch the bot on in a
conversation — that is the whole setup. No external daemon, no webhook endpoint,
no Docker image and no separate machine are required: the bot runs entirely inside
Nextcloud as a Talk in-app bot, in a few hundred kilobytes of PHP.

### Light by design

One small app, installed from the App Store like any other. There is nothing else
to run and nothing else to keep alive. It answers off the request path, so posting
a message never waits for the model.

### Bring your own model — or your own subscription

- **Native and OpenAI-compatible.** Anthropic Claude and Google Gemini through
  their own APIs, plus **any OpenAI-compatible endpoint**: OpenRouter, DeepSeek,
  Qwen/DashScope, Mistral, Groq, OpenAI itself, or a local server such as Ollama,
  vLLM or LM Studio.
- **Use a CLI subscription instead of API tokens.** If a Claude or Gemini command
  line tool is installed on the server, the bot can drive it — so a flat-rate
  subscription answers your users, with no per-token API bill. Off by default.
- **Pick the model from a list.** The settings page fetches the models your key
  can actually use, so there is nothing to type by hand, and only one place to set
  it. A connection test confirms it answers before your users try it.

### Two tiers: helpers for everyone, maintenance for admins

- **Ordinary users get a sandbox.** No tools, no files, no shell, no way to touch
  the server — just a helpful assistant that answers questions.
- **Administrators can get real access, only if you turn it on.** When the CLI
  engine is used, you may grant the members of the Nextcloud admin group tools
  that run with the web server's rights, so they can look into and maintain the
  server straight from a Talk conversation. Everyone who is not an administrator
  stays in the sandbox. Both tiers are empty by default.

### And the rest

- **Per-conversation memory.** Each user keeps their own history in every room;
  `/reset` starts over. Slash commands: `/help`, `/reset`, `/status`.
- **Access control.** Optionally restrict the bot to an allow-list of users.
- **Reply language.** Answer always in a fixed language, or mirror the user.

### Privacy

Messages sent to the bot go to the AI provider you configure, and nowhere else.
API keys are stored encrypted in the Nextcloud configuration and are never sent
back to the browser. Point the bot at a local model server and nothing leaves your
machine at all.

Requires the Nextcloud Talk app.
	]]></description>

	<description lang="ja"><![CDATA[
**Talk-Bot** は、Nextcloud Talk の会話をそのまま AI チャットにするアプリです。

アプリを有効化し、管理設定に API キーを入れ、会話でボットをオンにする——設定はこれだけです。
外部デーモンも Webhook の受け口も Docker イメージも別マシンも不要で、ボットは Talk の
アプリ内ボットとして、数百KBの PHP だけで Nextcloud の中だけで動作します。

### 軽さが身上

App Store から普通のアプリと同じようにインストールする、1つの小さなアプリです。
別に動かし続けるものはありません。応答はリクエストの外で作るので、メッセージの送信が
生成完了まで待たされることもありません。

### 好きなモデルを、あるいは手持ちのサブスクを

- **ネイティブ＋OpenAI互換。** Anthropic Claude と Google Gemini はそれぞれの
  ネイティブAPIで、さらに **OpenAI互換のエンドポイントすべて**（OpenRouter・DeepSeek・
  Qwen/DashScope・Mistral・Groq・OpenAI 本家、Ollama や vLLM、LM Studio などのローカル
  サーバー）に対応します。
- **APIトークンの代わりにCLIのサブスクを使えます。** サーバーに Claude や Gemini の
  コマンドラインツールが入っていれば、ボットがそれを使えます。定額のサブスクリプションで
  利用者に応答でき、従量課金のAPI料金は不要です。既定では無効です。
- **モデルは一覧から選べます。** 設定画面がキーで実際に使えるモデルを取得するので、
  手で打つ必要はなく、指定する場所も1か所だけです。接続テストで、利用者より先に応答を
  確認できます。

### 二段構え：全員にはアシスタント、管理者にはメンテナンスも

- **一般ユーザーはサンドボックス。** ツールなし・ファイルなし・シェルなし、サーバーに
  触れる手段はありません。質問に答えるだけのアシスタントです。
- **管理者には、有効化したときだけ本当のアクセスを。** CLIエンジン利用時に限り、
  Nextcloud の admin グループのメンバーへ、Webサーバー権限で動くツールを与えられます。
  Talk の会話からそのままサーバーを調べ、メンテナンスできます。管理者以外は常に
  サンドボックスのままです。どちらの段も既定では空（＝無効）です。

### その他

- **会話ごとの記憶。** 各ユーザーが各ルームで自分の履歴を保持します。`/reset` で
  やり直せます。スラッシュコマンド： `/help`、`/reset`、`/status`。
- **利用制限。** 許可ユーザーの一覧で利用者を絞れます。
- **返答の言語。** 常に特定の言語で返す／利用者に合わせる、を選べます。

### プライバシー

ボットに送られたメッセージは、設定した AI プロバイダーにのみ送信されます。
API キーは Nextcloud の設定に暗号化して保存され、ブラウザーへ返されることはありません。
ローカルのモデルサーバーを指定すれば、データは一切サーバーの外に出ません。

Nextcloud Talk アプリが必要です。
	]]></description>

	<version>2.0.0</version>
	<licence>agpl</licence>
	<author>KTEC</author>
	<namespace>TalkBot</namespace>
	<category>integration</category>
	<category>tools</category>

	<website>https://github.com/ktec-nc-apps/Talk-Bot</website>
	<bugs>https://github.com/ktec-nc-apps/Talk-Bot/issues</bugs>
	<repository type="git">https://github.com/ktec-nc-apps/Talk-Bot.git</repository>

	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ktec-nc-apps/Talk-Bot/main/screenshots/01-chat.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ktec-nc-apps/Talk-Bot/main/screenshots/02-settings.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ktec-nc-apps/Talk-Bot/main/screenshots/03-models.png</screenshot>

	<dependencies>
		<php min-version="8.1"/>
		<nextcloud min-version="30" max-version="32"/>
	</dependencies>

	<repair-steps>
		<post-migration>
			<step>OCA\TalkBot\Migration\RegisterBot</step>
		</post-migration>
	</repair-steps>

	<commands>
		<command>OCA\TalkBot\Command\Status</command>
		<command>OCA\TalkBot\Command\Rooms</command>
		<command>OCA\TalkBot\Command\Test</command>
	</commands>

	<settings>
		<admin>OCA\TalkBot\Settings\AdminTools</admin>
		<admin-section>OCA\TalkBot\Sections\Admin\TalkBotSection</admin-section>
	</settings>
</info>
